Calvin Chun-yu Chan

hello@calvincchan.com Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada Web: <u>calvincchan.com</u> Github: <u>github.com/calvincchan</u> Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/calvincchan</u>



PROFILE

As an experienced full-stack developer who has been working on startup projects for the last 10 years, I have a track record of delivering fully functional products with limited resources, ever-changing requirements, and a continuously evolving tech stack. For the most part, I have worked solo or with a handful of team members. I am happy to accept challenges and venture into areas I am not familiar with.

SKILLS

ES6 • Typescript • NodeJS • ExpressJS • Fastify • Supabase • ReactJS • MongoDB • PostgreSQL • Docker

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

EDU.INK Limited, Hong Kong

Jun 2019 - Present

- Led the development of multiple products, including a student information system, admission and enrolment system, billing and online payment system, library system, parent-teacher communication platform, and mobile apps.
- Led the transition from a single monolithic PHP app to modular and containerized NodeJS/MongoDBbased API servers, web console, and mobile client apps, resulting in improved scalability, functionality, and cost savings for end-users and stakeholders.
- <u>Backend</u>: NodeJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Typescript, Jest, Supabase, Docker. Fastify for the API framework. OpenAPI for documentation and API input validation and serialization
- 3rd party integrations: Powerschool, eTapestry, Active Directory, Stripe, OneSignal, S3, Google Cloud.
- Frontend & mobile app: VueJS, ReactJS, React Native.
- CI & Infrastructure: CircleCI, BitBucket Pipeline, AWS EC2, Docker.

Full Stack Developer

GUZZU, Hong Kong

Jun 2017 - Sep 2019

- Developed and deployed an e-commerce platform catering to small expat merchants in China. Created
 an array of products such as inventory management system, shopping applications for web and mobile,
 WeChat integration, online payment gateway, customizable storefront, and e-ticket issuance and
 redemption system.
- <u>Backend</u>: NodeJS, MongoDB, Redis. <u>Frontend</u>: AngularJS, WeChat Mini Program SDK.

Full Stack Developer

Giftpass Limited, Hong Kong

Mar 2013 - Jun 2017

- As a part of a China Accelerator Startup Project, I designed and implemented a digital gift voucher platform that streamlined the process for consumers, merchants.
- Backend: NodeJS, MongoDB, Apple Wallet SDK. Frontend: AngularJS.

UX Designer Genesix Inc., Japan May 2011 - Jul 2012

Designed user experience, interface, and visual design for iOS app targeting Japanese market.
 Collaborated with development team to create intuitive interfaces and visually appealing graphics that received positive feedback from users and increased downloads and engagement.

Web Designer and Engineer

A.C.O. Inc., Japan

Sep 2010 - Mar 2011

- Created websites for international clients using web design, rapid prototyping, and UI engineering skills with technologies like Fireworks and JQuery.
- Developed a Facebook Page and social application for global marketing initiatives that successfully increased brand awareness and user engagement.

InnateDB Software Developer The University of British Columbia, Canada Mar 2007 - Jun 2010

- Designed and implemented a search engine and management system for international innateimmunology experiments (<u>innatedb.ca</u>), incorporating data visualization and report generation capabilities.
- Developed intuitive UI for the management systems that facilitated ease of use and efficient data management.

Software Developer

Active Logic Inc., Canada

Jun 2006 - Feb 2007

• Developed customer management system for an online gaming platform.

Software Engineer &

System Administrator

ehosting.ca, Canada

May 2003 - Aug 2005

• Performed customer management software development, hosting product development, Linux server administration, and MySQL database management.

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia — B.Sc., Computer Science, 2000 - 2003